[Episode 9]
[Tomb of Zhang]
Over here.
Sir, look! We just dug this up.
How dare you!
What are you doing?
Are you even human?
This is utterly inhuman!
Give me back my mother!
Murder!
You're completely lawless!
His family's grave was also dug up.
Master Lv Da, this is a gift for you.
But please, return my mother's body to me.
Let her rest in peace, please.
This is just the ransom.
The ransom?
This hill and its land belong to us now.
None of you are allowed
to bury your family members here
unless you pay us for the burial annually.
I'll have my men find a nice place
to bury your mother. How about that?
Mother!
How can this be allowed?
For generations, this hill has
been the burial ground for our loved ones.
Since when did it become yours?
- Exactly!
- That's right!
Since when did it become your property?
What are you doing?
Let go of me!
Aren't you afraid of retribution?
- Heavens!
- Let go of me!
Retribution?
The dead can't exact retribution.
What do we do?
What can we do? There's nothing we can do.
Hurry back and gather the money!
Go gather the money.
Mr. Jia, he wanted his father's body back.
Look, I've reunited him with his father.
Yes, sure.
Sure.
And you? What's your decision?
Either you take your mother's body back home,
or--
I'll buy it back.
Hand over the money!
Do not let Mr. Lv say it twice!
Come here. Who told you to come?
Brother,
the gang leader didn't give me any jobs.
I have too much time on my hands.
You're collecting burial fees, right?
I can do it too.
Don't you know
why you're not allowed to work?
Don't you know what a huge mistake you made?
If the gang leader didn't have connections,
our gang would have been exposed.
Brother, can't I follow you?
Get lost, now!
- Please!
- Get lost!
Keep digging!
Got it.
After ten years of arduous study,
today, I'll finally stand
before the emperor as his subject.
Miss Meng, the robe looks good on you.
But when you enter the hall,
don't get weak in the knees.
Mr. Shen, did it happen to you
on your first day at court?
Of course not.
Then can you tell me
what His Majesty is like at court?
Have you heard a saying?
Being with the sovereign is
like being with a tiger.
I've heard it.
When His Majesty gets angry,
everyone gets scared.
Last month,
a colleague was dismissed
for saying one extra word in his report.
And another colleague
angered His Majesty and was directly...
But don't worry.
For Zhi Li's sake, I won't stand idly by.
If anyone targets you, I will--
Miss Meng, I haven't finished yet!
His Majesty has arrived.
Your Majesty. May Your Majesty be blessed!
Everyone, rise.
[Shen Mansion]
Thank you.
Zhi Li, the weather is chilly.
Be careful not to catch a cold.
What's bothering my brilliant sister?
I must say a drink can solve anything.
It seems something is truly troubling you.
His Majesty has transferred me
to the Censorate as an Assistant Director
and help Miss Meng solve crimes
in the capital.
His Majesty put you in an important position.
But this appointment is rather sudden.
I wasn't told either before.
The Censorate handles corruption cases,
involving dangerous conflicts.
I'm averse to bloodshed
and prefer a quiet environment.
I'm clearly more suited
to work at the Hanlin Academy.
Listen, His Majesty must have his reasons
for his decision.
Solving crimes needs your brain,
not brute strength.
You've been clever since childhood.
What others can't accomplish
is a piece of cake for you.
You make it sound easy.
The Censorate has just been established.
Not to mention those difficult ruffians,
those hypocritical court officials
must have created many barriers in secret.
And even you can't read His Majesty's mind.
How can I not be worried?
Zhi Shu, Zhi Li's concerns are reasonable.
The Hanlin Academy is peaceful
and most suited to her.
But this transfer from His Majesty
came suddenly.
How about we persuade His Majesty
to change his mind tomorrow?
Nian understands me best.
I don't know
why His Majesty made this decision,
but I believe
he must have thought a lot about this.
After all, he won't harm Zhi Li.
Zhi Shu, I think
- His Majesty--
- Nian.
Listen, His Majesty treats us
like his own siblings.
He relies on us and trusts us the most.
Now is the time to employ capable people.
Apart from Zhi Li,
who else is qualified for this position?
Since His Majesty has arranged it so,
I shall take it.
There you go.
You and Miss Meng will surely
make those corrupt officials tremble in fear.
Well, am I some kind of fearsome beast?
You're even sitting so far from me.
Back when we studied together,
Your Majesty was just more perceptive.
And now, Your Majesty controls Gu Qin
and targets Xu Ting as well.
You're quite moody.
If we speak or act improperly...
The four of us grew up together.
You always lose your manners in front of me.
So, are you going
to make a startling speech again? Go ahead.
But you mustn't get angry, Your Majesty.
At least, don't be mad while bathing.
Just pretend you were still the Crown Prince.
Fine.
How dare you!
Shen Zhi Shu!
I was just testing the waters.
Your Majesty promised me not to get angry.
I'm not angry.
I just suddenly recalled how I dealt with you
when I was the Crown Prince.
Your Majesty, please!
Nian, help!
I haven't relaxed like this for a long time.
At 16, I toured the whole nation
on behalf of the late emperor.
But now, I have to pick a fine time
for leaving the palace.
Your Majesty pretended to be drunk
and made Xu Ting so angry that he fell ill.
Why are you still troubled?
He's not really sick.
Half the court officials
submit their memorials to him.
He's clearly acting as a regent at his house.
I embarrassed him,
so he wants to fight back.
The memorials I got
are either about the strict evaluations
of female officials' performance,
or urging me to marry an empress
to stabilize the state.
Xu Ting is clearly putting on airs
as a senior official,
waiting for Your Majesty
to personally invite him back.
The Censorate has just been established,
so I'm happy not to see him now
in case he causes trouble.
Yesterday, Lord Gu used art appreciation
as a pretext to invite Miss Meng and Zhi Li.
This seems like an attempt to win them over.
I heard from Zhi Li
that he is attentive to the Censorate
and said he would spare no effort to assist.
He clearly started a confrontation
with Lord Xu.
Miss Meng is probably in for a rough time.
If she can't even handle this,
how can she manage the Censorate?
I don't know about her,
but Zhi Li definitely can't handle it.
But speaking of which,
I understand why Lord Xu urged you to marry.
Leaving aside your handsome face,
you have a bad temper.
Your mantra: "Insolent",
"How dare you", and "Leave!"
What girl will dare approach you?
How dare you.
See, I wasn't wrong.
Zhi Li and Your Majesty grew up together.
When she was little, she was close to you.
Now, her gaze towards her teacher
is much gentler than towards Your Majesty.
Nonsense!
Zhi Li only respects Lord Gu.
Lord Gu is nearly 50 and has a family.
He always puts on airs.
How could Zhi Li possibly--
Come on, you know nothing but wrestling
with the Divine Guard, don't you?
You don't understand a girl at all.
Your Majesty, don't always keep a stern face.
Otherwise, no girls will dare approach you.
Don't I smile most of the time?
Sure, but with malice.
It's scarier than when you don't smile.
Then tell me,
who else dares to be disrespectful to you?
Who?
None of your business!
Come on, let's drink.
Cheers!
Your Majesty, I was right, wasn't I?
Two hours have already passed.
Are you sure you want to continue?
[Censorate]
Miss Meng.
Let me help.
Thank you.
Miss Shen, did you move your study here?
I just brought some items I'm used to.
I originally thought of bringing two maids
for cleaning,
but I feared Zhi Shu and Nian would mock me
for turning the office into a boudoir.
I almost forgot the most important thing.
I planted this myself. It's a gift for you.
You can place it on your desk,
and it's best for calming the mind.
Indeed, it smells good.
On our first day,
let's turn this cheerless Censorate
[Censorate]
into the best local office, shall we?
Sure.
[Censorate]
I can't believe this!
The Censorate answers only to His Majesty.
Yet today, on our first day,
the building hasn't even been repaired.
The Censorate is separate
from the two chancellors and six ministries.
I'm an eyesore to Lord Xu.
The Minister of Revenue, Wen Tao, is his man,
so he won't approve the funds.
It's also a perfect opportunity
to show me who's the boss.
But it's just about repairing a building.
I'm most familiar with that.
Go find a cool place to rest.
Leave this to me.
Miss Meng, today is your first day in office.
How can you do the work yourself?
How about I go back
and get some servants to help?
It's fine. No need to trouble yourself.
Who's up there?
Miss Meng, we've met before.
You are?
I'm Yin Qing, a pharmacist from the palace.
What are you doing here?
No one here buys rouge and powder.
Hold on.
In the palace, I was forced by circumstances.
But since you handed me over to Captain Di,
I've come to my senses.
I've now turned over a new leaf.
If you need spices, I'll give them for free.
What is this for?
To ward off evil spirits.
Peach wood dispels evil spirits,
and bronze mirrors reflect evil energy.
After all, it's a haunted house.
They help you sleep soundly at night.
Haunted house?
Miss Meng, Miss Shen, here is the thing.
This place was the interrogation wing
of the Ministry of Justice's prison.
I heard that anyone who was interrogated here
committed suicide out of fear of punishment.
Later, because it was too eerie,
it was abandoned.
This is utterly outrageous!
How could they let us work here?
Miss Meng, yesterday, Lord Gu said
that if anyone deliberately makes trouble,
he would definitely not stand idly by.
Let's go to him now.
Wait.
Miss Shen, don't be afraid.
I've long prepared for this.
Once I finish this ritual,
whatever evil spirits will be gone.
She faints at the sight of blood.
Miss Meng.
- Zhi Li.
- This is the balm I developed.
It can help restore the spirit
and refresh the mind.
Wait, does this medicine really work?
Miss, you can doubt my character,
but you can't question my medical skill.
She's awake.
Your mouth.
Zhi Li.
- Zhi Li.
- One more time.
What's that smell? It stinks!
It helps refresh your mind.
Miss, Miss Shen has just come
and already encountered troubles.
It shows the negative energy here is strong.
Well, why don't you wear my bracelet
to ward off evil?
I don't need it. I'm a tough girl.
I'll take it. I'll pay any price.
It costs only ten taels.
Of course, five taels is also acceptable.
For Miss Meng's sake,
I'll give it to you for free.
That's very kind of you.
Miss Meng, do you think I'm too weak
to handle the position
and will hold you back?
What are you talking about?
When you made a promise before the Xu's,
I could tell you were not a weak young lady.
To be honest,
I thought you'd decline to come
in case you work in dangerous situations.
But today, you came with your elegance.
I was surprised and delighted.
But I never expected you to come.
What exactly is your purpose?
Miss Meng, I heard
that His Majesty established the Censorate
and allowed you
to personally select your assistants.
I wish to work for you, and for His Majesty.
So, you got the roof fixed?
Yes. In the palace,
I always go wherever I'm needed.
I often do the work of two.
If you two need anything,
just command me as you wish.
Although I'm not good at martial arts,
I'm proficient in things
like feng shui, geomancy,
skin care, detoxification,
mechanical devices,
and numerology.
Are you really just a minor official?
You sound more like a legendary figure
from a storybook.
You flatter me.
Miss Meng, this is my latest creation.
It's not smelly.
Pearl Whitening Powder, enhanced version.
I noticed you've gotten a bit sun-tanned.
I'm not interested in this.
Let me take a look.
What is your real purpose?
Miss, since the case of
the true and false Huiyuan,
and then the restoration
of the Imperial Exam for Women,
I've admired you greatly.
You have courage, talent,
capability, and...
Anyway, you're different from
those pedantic people.
Both you and I came from humble origins.
If I could follow you,
I would surely have a bright future.
Of course, I'm here to pledge my loyalty.
If I didn't have some skills,
how could I have the nerve to come?
Miss, this is a new poison I made.
It's called Myriad Colors.
It's colorless and odorless.
One sip will make a person
lose their fighting ability.
You want to poison me?
I'm parched.
Imperial Guard Huang, are you feeling fine?
Are you feeling fine?
Sure.
Miss Meng, it's your first day.
His Majesty sent me to check on you.
If you encounter any trouble,
just use this to command the Divine Guard.
You can also directly report to His Majesty.
Imperial Guard Huang, your voice...
What about my voice?
Is this my voice? What's wrong with my voice?
Yin Qing, the antidote?
Imperial Guard Huang, take this.
In half an hour,
you'll recover your incredible male voice.
How am I supposed to speak
to His Majesty like this?
It won't last for life, will it?
Can I really get my voice back?
This medicine is just developed.
It probably has some side effects.
Listen, go back and sleep on it today.
You should be better tomorrow.
How dare you poison me!
No, it's not like that.
Miss Meng, I originally wanted
to demonstrate this medicine on myself.
But he came and just drank it. I...
Are you out of your mind?
What normal person would poison themselves?
I now suspect you of poisoning me.
You're coming with me right now.
Help, Miss Meng!
- Miss Meng!
- Imperial Guard Huang.
Yin Qing is another colleague of mine.
This is a misunderstanding.
Please let him go.
Imperial Guard Huang,
I can attest he planned to take the medicine.
You better not be caught by me again!
I'll take my leave now.
Take care.
Miss Meng, so I can work here?
You just saved my life.
You're my lucky star, my lifesaver!
From now on,
whatever you say, I'll listen to you.
Miss Meng, are we really keeping him?
The Censorate is small,
but it will never hire useless people.
You, stay for now, on probation.
Not small, and I'm useful.
Probation is good. I'll go work now.
[Censorate]
Miss Meng, what are you looking at?
Nothing.
Where did you find these people?
Their wives and daughters
are all my regular customers.
I promised that if they come to help,
they can buy rouge from me at half price.
You really are a jack-of-all-trades.
You're quite good at business.
If Fu Zhi knows you,
you two will definitely get along.
I don't have plans to get married yet.
You wish.
By the way, let's not talk about me.
The backyard is tidied up,
and the meal is ready.
Let's eat now.
Don't put it there. Move it over a bit.
Miss Meng, Miss Shen.
I personally made some dishes.
Please try them.
You sit down and eat with us too.
Thank you so much.
Go ahead.
Yin Qing, you're good at cooking.
Miss Shen, is the food not to your liking?
No, I'm a tiny bit picky about food.
If you have any issues, please tell me.
I'll definitely do it better.
Actually, not many issues.
For this asparagus lettuce with pork,
the asparagus lettuce should be cut
into smaller pieces to absorb the flavor.
The meat should be sliced
as thin as possible.
And for this soup,
the mushrooms must be picked
early in the morning.
Those picked after noon
will have an earthy smell.
And for this stir-fried vegetable,
the salt should be sprinkled lightly,
and less oil should be added.
Ideally, no soy sauce should be added
to preserve the original flavor.
I'm just saying. Don't take it to heart.
Actually, I'm not very hungry.
That's good then.
Now that we've officially started to work,
we must uproot the Huxiao Gang
and the forces behind it.
We can talk with the Supreme Court
and the Capital Prefectural Office
to retrieve the relevant case files.
But currently, the various ministries
are quite critical of the Censorate.
If we follow this procedure,
it might take almost half a month.
If someone deliberately makes trouble,
we can ask His Majesty for help.
I can also ask my teacher to help negotiate.
But if we have to trouble His Majesty
and Lord Gu for such a small matter,
won't that make people think
the Censorate is a soft touch?
Then Miss, what's your plan?
Gangs do evil
simply to amass ill-gotten wealth.
And it's the safest way to accumulate wealth
under the guise of prosperity.
We might find some clues on Changle Street.
Once Bofeng House opens,
it can be a place to gather intelligence.
Yin Qing.
Yes?
Go get a brass gong.
I'm going to do something big.
Got it.
[Heavy Reward for Clues
Related to the Huxiao Gang]
The Censorate is handling a case!
His Majesty established the Censorate
to solve crimes.
Anyone with information about the Huxiao Gang
can come to the Censorate to report it.
What is the Huxiao Gang?
And what crime did they commit?
The court actually
made such a big deal about this.
Since the court sent a female official
to investigate the case,
it's probably not a major case.
Get out of here.
Leave, everyone.
- You...
- Let's go.
There's nothing special to see. Let's go.
- It's boring.
[Heavy Reward for Clues
Related to the Huxiao Gang]
Miss, this method doesn't seem to be working.
It seems
the Huxiao Gang committed crimes in secret,
while the Heihu Crew did evil openly.
The whole Shazhou knew it.
But as far as I know,
there are quite a few citizens
who come to the Capital Prefectural Office
and the Supreme Court
to complain about ruffians and injustices.
The Censorate is meant to protect the people.
Anyone who commits crimes
or bullies the weak can be reported.
I will definitely seek justice for you.
[Heavy Reward for Clues
Related to the Huxiao Gang]
Miss Meng, let me carry it.
I didn't expect
to see such a dilapidated place.
Mostly, the poor, refugees,
and beggars gather north of the city.
Miss Shen, you were born
into a prestigious family east of the city.
Naturally, you've never been here.
Miss Meng.
[In Mourning]
We've already sold everything we could.
I also borrowed 20 taels from my parents.
But we're still short by more than ten taels.
Thank you.
You were severely injured
by those corpse thieves.
You must not get out of bed.
[In Mourning]
Grandmother, I'm so sorry.
They stole Grandfather's body
and demanded a high ransom for its return.
But we simply can't gather enough money
to redeem Grandfather's body.
Now, even though you've passed away,
I dare not bury you.
I'm afraid
those evil thieves will steal your body
and come to extort us again.
Grandmother, we truly have no way out.
Who's outside?
We're from the Censorate.
I saw you on the street just now.
Get out! Right now!
We mean no harm.
Just now on the street, you looked worried.
I'm afraid you're in trouble,
so I came to check on you.
The Censorate is directly under His Majesty
and acts on behalf of His Majesty.
Speaking to Miss Meng is the same
as speaking to His Majesty.
Miss.
Cheng.
Cheng, you can't say.
If you speak,
Grandfather's body won't be redeemed.
We reported our case to the authorities,
but they considered it minor and ignored it.
Instead, we were threatened
and retaliated against by the corpse thieves.
Miss, we're truly helpless.
Corpse thieves?
Look, what do you think of my outfit today?
I always claimed
to be the hottest man on Changle Street.
But seeing Your Majesty's appearance today,
I can only surrender that title.
If the noble ladies saw Your Majesty,
wouldn't they all drool?
Alright, enough flattery.
How do we leave the palace now?
I was recently looking through old archives
and discovered an abandoned passage
that leads directly outside the palace.
Lead the way.
[Huiyin House]
Cousin,
during my tenure as the Envoy of Customs,
I worked so hard and traveled a lot.
I finally found this...
The rules here are quite interesting.
One must submit a name card
half a month in advance for an appointment.
Each guest proposes a theme,
and the musician improvises a piece.
At the end of the music, they offer tea
that hints at the music's meaning.
Situ Xue, the owner of this place,
has become famous in these two years.
She's known as the top dancer in the capital.
Many spend a fortune just to watch her.
Cousin, at the Flower Festival,
you praised the blossom mark on her forehead.
Alright, what about the clues?
Cousin, we've just come. What's the rush?
In this place,
you must first learn to enjoy yourself.
After you.
It is indeed the Xiyan flower.
Mr. Shen.
It's been a few days. And you look prettier.
Mr. Shen, it's been quite a while
since you last visited Huiyin House.
Many noble ladies have been waiting
to meet you.
And who is this gentleman?
This is my distant cousin, He Du.
He's been feeling down lately
and came to me to have fun.
He heard your music can cheer listeners up.
So he came specifically to listen.
My cousin is unapproachable.
I hope you won't mind.
Since he's your friend,
I naturally dare not neglect him.
This quiet room is best
for one person to clear the mind.
Cousin, take your time.
Thank you.
The Huiyin House is quite famous,
and so is your music.
Your reputation is truly well-deserved.
You flatter me, sir.
I noticed you kept glancing at the screen.
You seem quite interested in it.
This quiet room is full of elegant greenery.
Only the purple flowers on this screen
are exceptionally showy.
You've broken the elegance with it.
It's quite ingenious.
Is there a meaning behind it?
Sure, there is.
Some time ago,
a folk music troupe from Beijian
passed through the capital
and stayed at my place.
I saw the unique floral decorations
on the musicians' foreheads.
So I specifically inquired about it.
This flower is called Xiyan.
It blooms at night and withers by morning.
In Beijian,
it symbolizes fleeting beauty and is popular.
This quiet room is elegant, but a bit dull.
I like Xiyan flowers,
so I had someone craft this screen.
If you like it, how about I give it to you?
I appreciate your kind offer,
but I have to decline.
But according to the books I read,
I learned
this kind of flower symbolizes extermination,
revenge, and hatred.
Sir, please be careful with your words.
Huiyin House opens its doors to guests
and values goodwill and harmony above all.
I have no grudge
against those Beijian people.
I don't think they would deceive me.
There's no need to be alarmed.
The meaning of flowers
is a reflection of our innate desire.
It's a matter of personal interpretation.
Sir, please have some tea.
Good tea.